<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
    License CC BY-NC-SA 3.0

   This work is licensed under the
   "Namensnennung – Keine kommerzielle Nutzung – Weitergabe unter
    gleichen Bedingungen 3.0 Deutschland (CC BY-NC-SA 3.0)"
   http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/de/deed.de

   Read the English translation here:

   "Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported (CC BY-NC-SA 3.0)"
   http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/

-->
<!--<?xml-model href="file:../5.1/dbref.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>-->

<section xml:id="dbc.common.fonts" remap="topic" userlevel="easy"
   xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
   xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
   xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <title>Finding Professional Fonts</title>
  <info>
    <definitions definitionfile="defs.xml"/>
    <keywordset>
      <keyword>fonts</keyword>
      <keyword>SIL</keyword>
      <keyword>Google Web Fonts</keyword>
      <keyword>CTAN</keyword>
      <keyword>Linux Libertine fonts</keyword>
      <keyword>DejaVu fonts</keyword>
      <keyword>Stix fonts</keyword>
    </keywordset>
    <subjectset>
      <subject>
        <subjectterm>fonts</subjectterm>
      </subject>
    </subjectset>
  </info>

  <section role="problem">
    <title>Problem</title>
    <para>You need to find professional fonts, preferably released under
      an open source license which can be used for print or web formats.</para>
  </section>
  <section role="solution">
    <title>Solution</title>
    <para>There are some very good fonts which can be used freely. Most
      fonts are even released under the <link
        xlink:href="http://scripts.sil.org/OFL">Open Font License</link>
      or other free or open licenses. The following list is a small
      overview which is by no means complete (also use your favorite
      search engine):</para>
    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term><link xlink:href="http://scripts.sil.org"/></term>
        <listitem>
          <para><acronym>SIL<alt>Summer Institute of
            Linguistics</alt></acronym> is a nonprofit organization for
            sustainable language development. One part is to <quote>support
            the use of non-Roman and complex scripts in language development.</quote>
            <acronym>SIL</acronym> creates the Charis SIL, Doulos SIL,
            Gentium, Andika, and other typefaces. All fonts are released
            under the Open Font License (OFL). This license was specially
            created for fonts and was initiated by SIL.
            </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term><link xlink:href="http://fonts.google.com"/></term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Google Web Fonts is a huge collection of open source
            fonts. They can be freely incorporated into your web sites
            using CSS or can be downloaded and embedded in PDF.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term><link xlink:href="http://www.tug.org/tetex/"/></term>
        <listitem>
          <para>The TeTeX distribution and <acronym>CTAN<alt>Comprehensive
            TeX Archive Network</alt></acronym> also contains some high quality
            fonts, however, mainly aimed at the print business and not for
          the web.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term><link xlink:href="http://www.linuxlibertine.org"/></term>
        <listitem>
          <para>The Linux Libertine fonts are designed to be an
            alternative to the serif Times fonts.
            The Linux Libertine and the Linux Biolinum fonts are a
            collection of serif and sans serif fonts with the usual
            Latin, Greek, Cyrillic, and Hebrew glyphs. Additionally, the fonts
            contain ligatures, true small caps, old style numbers,
            proportional or monospaced numbers, true superscript and
            subscript, and much more. A monospace variant is currently
            being designed.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term><link xlink:href="https://dejavu-fonts.github.io/"/></term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
          The DejaVu font family is derived from the Bitstream Vera fonts.
          Due to license issues, the font has to be renamed. The fonts
          now contain lots of glyphs and support Latin, Greek, Cyrillic,
          Armenian, Georgian, and other languages.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term><link xlink:href="http://www.stixfonts.org"/></term>
        <listitem>
          <para>The STIX fonts (Scientific and Technical Information Exchange)
          is a set of comprehensive fonts for scientific and engineering
          manuscripts. They can be used both for print and online publishing. </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term><link xlink:href="https://www.websiteplanet.com/blog/best-free-fonts/ "/></term>
        <listitem>
          <para>A collection of more than 70 free fonts which are also free for commercial use.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

  </section>
  <section role="discussion">
    <title>Discussion</title>
    <para>Before you use a font, answer the following questions:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <formalpara>
          <title>Supported Languages and Amount of Glyphs</title>
          <para>Does your font support your language? Although modern
            fonts use Unicode these days, your language
            might not be supported. Especially if you need
              <quote>uncommon</quote> languages or rarely used glyphs.
          </para>
        </formalpara>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <formalpara>
          <title>Missing Styles</title>
          <para>Some fonts are published in one style only, usually
            <emphasis>regular</emphasis>. Such fonts make it more difficult
            to universally adopt them in different scenarios where more
            styles (bold, italic, or a combination) are needed.
          </para>
        </formalpara>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <formalpara>
          <title>Font Formats</title>
          <para>Modern fonts are usually Unicode fonts published in <acronym>OTF<alt
            >OpenType Font</alt></acronym> or <acronym>TTF<alt>TrueType Font</alt></acronym>
            format. Older fonts are mostly PostScript Type 1 fonts which
            have a limited amount of glphys (theoretically 256).
            PostScript fonts cannot be used on the web.</para>
        </formalpara>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <formalpara>
          <title>Font Combinations</title>
          <para>For a non-designer, it is generally easier to use a
            complete font family conisting of sans serif, serif and
            monospaced typefaces. The reason for this is that these typefaces
            are made to match. It is much more difficult to
            select fonts that suit aesthetically as it needs
            experience.</para>
        </formalpara>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <formalpara>
          <title>Quality</title>
          <para>This is a broad topic and it heavily depends on where you want to
            use the font. Is it primarily used for web content or 
            for print only? Or both? Some fonts only look good on a web
            page, others only go with printed documents. Sometimes the
            <emphasis>hinting</emphasis> (adjustment of a font to a
            certain resolution) may or may not be implemented.
          </para>
        </formalpara>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
</section>
