<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
    License CC BY-NC-SA 3.0
  
   This work is licensed under the 
   "Namensnennung – Keine kommerzielle Nutzung – Weitergabe unter
    gleichen Bedingungen 3.0 Deutschland (CC BY-NC-SA 3.0)" 
   http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/de/deed.de
   
   Read the English translation here:
   
   "Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported (CC BY-NC-SA 3.0)" 
   http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/
   
-->

<preface xml:id="dbc.preface"
   xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
   xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
   xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <info>
    <xi:include href="defs.xml"/>
  </info>
  <title>Welcome!</title>
  <blockquote>
    <title>Mission</title>
    <para>The <citetitle
        xlink:href="https://sourceforge.net/projects/doccookbook/"
        >DocCookBook</citetitle> project aims to create a collection of
      cookbook-style solutions released under an open source license
      for the international DocBook community.</para>
  </blockquote>
  
  <para>
    DocBook is a XML format to write documentation mostly for hard-
    and software, but is not limited to this domain. With the help of
    the DocBook XSL stylesheets, text can be published into different
    target formats. </para>
  <para>
    Although there are helpful and valuable documentation like the
      <citetitle xlink:href="http://www.docbook.org/tdg51/en/html/docbook.html"
        >DocBook&#xa0;5: The Definitive Guide</citetitle> from <personname>
      <firstname>Norman</firstname>
      <surname>Walsh</surname>
    </personname> and <personname>
      <firstname>Bob</firstname>
      <surname>Stayton</surname>
    </personname>'s <citetitle xlink:href="http://www.sagehill.net/docbookxsl/"
      >DocBook XSL</citetitle> book, until now
    nobody wrote a book that combines the <emphasis>best of both
    worlds</emphasis>. My book is intented to be such a book. However, 
    it <emphasis>does not</emphasis> want to replace the prior mentioned 
    de facto standards. It aims for <emphasis>enhancing</emphasis> 
    the world of DocBook.
  </para>
  <para>
    My book is a collection of problem-and-solution scenarios
    written in a cookbook style. It is the nature of such a topic that
    there might be some overlap with the books above. However, 
    it also goes beyond them to get a better and deeper understanding
    from the world of DocBook. I think, we benefit from different
    opinions and sights.
  </para>
  <para>
    The scenarios are mostly based on my own experiences with DocBook 
    and the DocBook XSL stylesheets. However, it also includes questions 
    and answers from other sources: mostly the DocBook mailinglists, but
    also other sites that I have found. When other authors inspired me, 
    I have included their names. If you think your name is missing,
    please let me know.
  </para>
  <para>
    As I have learned a lot from the masters of DocBook, it is time to
    give something back. This book is written and available under a 
    Creative Commons license. I hope the DocBook community will find it useful.
  </para>
  
  <section xml:id="dbc.preface.audience">
    <title>Audience</title>
    <para>This book does not attempt to teach you DocBook or any other
      related technology (with the exception of <xref
        linkend="dbc.markup"/>). It is targetted more for DocBook
      developers who seek concise examples for their problems. However,
      with some try-and-error it can also be useful for ordenary writers
      who wants to customize their documents. Readers who want further
      information, I have included some links in the <citetitle>See
        Also</citetitle> section at the end of the topic. </para>
  </section>
  
  <section xml:id="dbc.preface.further-reading">
    <title>Further Readings</title>
    <para>By no means is this book complete. As this book is based on
      technologies like CSS, XML, (X)HTML, and XSLT, it is always a good
      idea to seek other information. I highly recommend to read the
      books from <personname>
        <firstname>Norman</firstname>
        <surname>Walsh</surname>
      </personname> and <personname>
        <firstname>Bob</firstname>
        <surname>Stayton</surname>
      </personname> as mentioned above.</para>
  </section>
  
  <section xml:id="dbc.preface.typo">
    <title>Typographical Conventions</title>
    <para>TBD</para>
  </section>
  
  <section xml:id="dbc.preface.feedback">
    <title>Feedback</title>
    <para>The project is hosted on <link xlink:show="new"
      xlink:href="https://sourceforge.net">SourceForge</link> under the
      name <link xlink:show="new"
        xlink:href="https://sourceforge.net/projects/doccookbook/">DocCookBook</link>.
      Feel free to send me praise, constructive criticism, suggestions,
      ideas, improvements, or anything else. If you want to contribute
      to this book, I'm more than happy to give you commit rights. Send
      me a mail to <link xlink:href="https://sourceforge.net/sendmessage.php?touser=27667"
        >tom_schr(AT)users.sourceforge.net</link>.
    </para>
  </section>
  
  <section xml:id="dbc.preface.contrib">
    <title>Contribute to the Book</title>
    <para>The source code of this book is published as a Mercurial
      repository. Feel free to clone it, make improvements and send me
      the changes. Getting a copy takes just a few seconds. If you have
      Mercurial already installed on your system, </para>
    <screen>hg clone https://hg.code.sf.net/p/doccookbook/code</screen>
    <remark>Add further notice about comment system or Mercurial?</remark>
  </section>
  
  <section xml:id="dbc.preface.ack">
    <title>Acknowledgments</title>
    <para>Such a large project is usually not a one man show. Many
    people contributed to this book:</para>
    
  </section>
</preface>
