<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<preface xml:id="dbc.preface"
   xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
   xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
   xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <title>Preface</title>
  <para>
    DocBook is a XML format to write documentation mostly for hard-
    and software, but is not limited to this domain. With the help of
    the DocBook XSL stylesheets, text can be published into different
    target formats. </para>
  <para>
    Although there are helpful and valuable documentation like the
      <citetitle>DocBook The Definitive Guide</citetitle> from <personname>
      <firstname>Norman</firstname>
      <surname>Walsh</surname>
    </personname> and <personname>
      <firstname>Bob</firstname>
      <surname>Stayton</surname>
    </personname>'s <citetitle>DocBook XSL</citetitle> book, until now
    nobody wrote a book that combines the <emphasis>best of both
    worlds</emphasis>. My book is intented to be such a book. However, 
    it <emphasis>does not</emphasis> want to replace the prior mentioned 
    de facto standards. It aims for <emphasis>enhancing</emphasis> 
    the world of DocBook.
  </para>
  <para>
    My book is a collection of problem-and-solution scenarios
    written in a cookbook style. It is the nature of such a topic that
    there might be some overlap with the previous books above. However, 
    I think, it is naturally and we always benefit from different
    opinions and sights. 
  </para>
  <para>
    The scenarios are mostly based on my own experiences with DocBook 
    and the DocBook XSL stylesheets. However, it also includes questions 
    and answers from the DocBook mailinglists, or interesting things
    that I have found from different Web sites. When I was inspired from
    other authors, I have included their names into it.
  </para>
  <para>
    As I have learned a lot from the masters of DocBook, it is time to
    give something back. This book is written under a Creative Commons
    license. I hope the DocBook community will find it useful.
  </para>

  <section>
    <title>Audience</title>
    <para>You should know at least DocBook, have heard (and
      even better worked!) with CSS and XSLT. This book does not
      attempt to teach you DocBook, XSLT, CSS, XSL-FO, or any other
      related technology. </para>
  </section>
  
  <section xml:id="dbc.preface.further-reading">
    <title>Further Reading</title>
    <para>By no means is this complete. It</para>
  </section>
  
  <section xml:id="dbc.preface.typo">
    <title>Typographical Conventions</title>
    <para>TBD</para>
  </section>
  
  <section xml:id="dbc.preface.contact">
    <title>How to Contact Me</title>
    <para>TBD</para>
  </section>
  
  <section xml:id="dbc.preface.ack">
    <title>Acknowledgments</title>
    <para>TBD</para>
  </section>
</preface>
